<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Medical Imaging | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/medical-imaging/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/medical-imaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Medical Imaging</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/media/icon_huc5fd9f1b4f03f2d64add7afcb374c1e6_29577_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Medical Imaging</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/medical-imaging/</link></image><item><title>PyKale: an ML Library in PyTorch Ecosystem</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</guid><description>&lt;p>PyKale is a library in the PyTorch ecosystem aiming to make machine learning more accessible to interdisciplinary research by bridging gaps between data, software, and end users. Both machine learning experts and end users can do better research with our accessible, scalable, and sustainable design, guided by green machine learning principles. PyKale has a unified pipeline-based API and focuses on multimodal learning and transfer learning for graphs, images, texts, and videos at the moment, with supporting models on deep learning and dimensionality reduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyKale enforces standardization and minimalism, via green machine learning concepts of reducing repetitions and redundancy, reusing existing resources, and recycling learning models across areas. PyKale will enable and accelerate interdisciplinary, knowledge-aware machine learning research for graphs, images, texts, and videos in applications including bioinformatics, graph analysis, image/video recognition, and medical imaging, with an overarching theme of leveraging knowledge from multiple sources for accurate and interpretable prediction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncertainty Est. for Landmark Localisation</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automatic anatomical landmark localisation has made great strides by leveraging deep learning methods in recent years. The ability to quantify the uncertainty of these predictions is a vital ingredient needed to see these methods adopted in clinical use, where it is imperative that erroneous predictions are caught and corrected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Quantile Binning, a data-driven method to categorise predictions by uncertainty with estimated error bounds. This framework can be applied to any continuous uncertainty measure, allowing straightforward identification of the best subset of predictions with accompanying estimated error bounds. We facilitate easy comparison between uncertainty measures by constructing two evaluation metrics derived from Quantile Binning. We demonstrate this framework by comparing and contrasting three uncertainty measures (a baseline, the current gold standard, and a proposed method combining aspects of the two), across two datasets (one easy, one hard) and two heatmap-based landmark localisation model paradigms (U-Net based and patch-based). We conclude by illustrating how filtering out gross mispredictions caught in our Quantile Bins significantly improves the proportion of predictions under an acceptable error threshold, and offer recommendations on which uncertainty measure to use and how to use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Human-In-The-Loop DL for Cardiac CT/MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/cardiac-hitl-dl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/cardiac-hitl-dl/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is an &lt;a href="https://fundingawards.nihr.ac.uk/award/AI_AWARD01706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NIHR AI in Health and Care Award&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular and pulmonary diseases account for close to half of all deaths in the UK. Diagnosing individuals with such conditions correctly and predicting whether they will respond to treatment is important to guide therapeutic intervention and achieve optimal outcomes. Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI) and computed tomography (CT) scans are key to cardiac and pulmonary diagnosis. Current assessments are made by manual measurements (contours or landmarks) to derive meaningful information of heart function, or physiological parameters that are time-consuming and suffer from variability between individuals due to human error. Artificial intelligence using deep learning is pushing the limit of image analysis to an unprecedented level. Recently, a deep learning-based method trained on scans with high variability has been shown to achieve fully automated assessment of the left ventricle (LV) on CMRI. However, this level of automation has not been achieved for the right ventricle (RV) or the atrial chambers. RV failure is the key determinant of death in many cardiac conditions, but accurate RV assessment by human observers is challenging due to the more subtle anatomy and the thinner structures. There is a real clinical need to develop a fully automated assessment of the RV and all four cardiac chambers to derive meaningful physiological parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this project is to develop an interactive human-in-the-loop multi-stage deep learning method to measure the health of the heart in large cohorts of patients with different cardiac and pulmonary conditions, scanned on different MRI/CT machines. This method will automatically generate physiological parameters and assess their ability to automatically predict treatment response and early death. In addition, we will assess the ability of machine learning to directly assess complex shape or/and motion of the heart to make a prognostic assessment from the automatic drawings on the heart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Existing contour and landmark detection algorithms (known from our pilot assessments to be suboptimal) will be applied to scans of a large cohort of patients from different hospitals with diverse cardiac and pulmonary conditions. The measurements will be edited by a team of experienced consultants, these revised contours and landmarks will be fed back into the training to achieve an improved segmentation, and the process will repeat three times to achieve ideal accuracy. Feedback will be sought from doctors, imaging experts and patients.The deep learnt assessment of the heart will provide important measurements for predicting therapy response and survival in individuals with cardiac disease. The automatic physiological parameters and assessment of complex shape or/and motion produced by the deep learning approach could revolutionise disease assessment, and improve treatment delivery and patient care. Key advantages are rapid assessment, minimised human error and more consistent reporting of cardiac physiology and function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multisite Brain fMRI Classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) has no objective diagnosis method despite having a high prevalence. Machine learning has been widely used to develop classification models for ASD using neuroimaging data. Recently, studies have shifted towards using large multi-site neuroimaging datasets to boost the clinical applicability and statistical power of results. However, the classification performance is hindered by the heterogeneous nature of agglomerative datasets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we propose new methods for multi-site autism classification using the Autism Brain Imaging Data Exchange (ABIDE) dataset. We firstly propose a new second-order measure of functional connectivity (FC) named as Tangent Pearson embedding to extract better features for classification. Then we assess the statistical dependence between acquisition sites and FC features, and apply a domain adaptation approach to minimise the site dependence of FC features to improve classification. Our analysis shows that 1) statistical dependence between site and FC features is statistically significant at the 5% level, and 2) extracting second-order features from neuroimaging data and minimising their site dependence can improve over state-of-the-art classification results on the ABIDE dataset, achieving a classification accuracy of 73%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpretable ML for Cardiac MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/ml-assess-cmr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/ml-assess-cmr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is a &lt;a href="https://grantnav.threesixtygiving.org/grant/360G-Wellcome-215799_Z_19_Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wellcome Trust Innovator Awards: Digital Technologies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular diseases account for 26% of deaths in the UK. Current clinical imaging assessments rely on manual or semi-automated measurements. Emerging approaches focus on individual parts of the heart. We have developed the first tensor-based machine learning approach that holistically assesses the heart and surrounding structures on cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI) scans. We will develop this approach into a tool that can identify patients who respond to treatment or who will die early. Key advantages are rapid holistic assessment, minimal human error and full transparency with direct visualisation of features for the disease. We will assemble a large cohort of CMRI scans from 5, 000 patients with pulmonary hypertension, a severe condition affecting the heart, and assess the ability to predict treatment response and likelihood of early death. This tool will revolutionise disease assessment, and improve treatment delivery and patient care.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>