<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bioinformatics | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/bioinformatics/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/bioinformatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Bioinformatics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/media/icon_huc5fd9f1b4f03f2d64add7afcb374c1e6_29577_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Bioinformatics</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/bioinformatics/</link></image><item><title>Low-Bias Evaluation of Drug-Target Interaction</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project-removed/dti-graph-eval/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project-removed/dti-graph-eval/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is in collaboration with AstraZeneca.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drug-target interaction (DTI) prediction is important in drug discovery and chemogenomics studies. Machine learning, particularly deep learning, has advanced this area significantly over the past few years. However, a significant gap between the performance reported in academic papers and that in practical drug discovery settings, e.g. the random-split-based evaluation strategy tends to be too optimistic in estimating the prediction performance in real-world settings. Such performance gap is largely due to hidden data bias in experimental datasets and inappropriate data split.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we construct a low-bias DTI dataset and study more challenging data split strategies to improve performance evaluation for real-world settings. Specifically, we study the data bias in a popular DTI dataset, BindingDB, and re-evaluate the prediction performance of three state-of-the-art deep learning models using five different data split strategies: random split, cold drug split, scaffold split, and two hierarchical-clustering-based splits. In addition, we comprehensively examine six performance metrics. Our experimental results confirm the overoptimism of the popular random split and show that hierarchical-clustering-based splits are far more challenging and can provide potentially more useful assessment of model generalizability in real-world DTI prediction settings.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>