<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rebecca Croasdale-Wood | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/rebecca-croasdale-wood/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/rebecca-croasdale-wood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Rebecca Croasdale-Wood</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/media/icon_huc5fd9f1b4f03f2d64add7afcb374c1e6_29577_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Rebecca Croasdale-Wood</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/rebecca-croasdale-wood/</link></image><item><title>Inverse protein folding via denoising diffusion</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/inverse-protein-folding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/inverse-protein-folding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Inverse protein folding generates valid amino acid sequences that can fold into a desired protein structure, with recent deep-learning advances showing significant potential and competitive performance. However, challenges remain in predicting highly uncertain regions, such as those with loops and disorders. To tackle such low-confidence residue prediction, we propose a &lt;strong>Ma&lt;/strong>sk &lt;strong>p&lt;/strong>rior-guided denoising &lt;strong>Diff&lt;/strong>usion (&lt;strong>MapDiff&lt;/strong>) framework that accurately captures both structural and residue interactions for inverse protein folding. MapDiff is a discrete diffusion probabilistic model that iteratively generates amino acid sequences with reduced noise, conditioned on a given protein backbone. To incorporate structural and residue interactions, we develop a graph-based denoising network with a mask prior pre-training strategy. Moreover, in the generative process, we combine the denoising diffusion implicit model with Monte-Carlo dropout to improve uncertainty estimation. Evaluation on four challenging sequence design benchmarks shows that MapDiff significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods. Furthermore, the in-silico sequences generated by MapDiff closely resemble the physico-chemical and structural characteristics of native proteins across different protein families and architectures.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>