<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/haiping-lu/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/haiping-lu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Haiping Lu</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/haiping-lu/avatar_huaea986fe85a28b20cb3e8d66de66f869_1846195_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/haiping-lu/</link></image><item><title>A GNN-based multi-task learning framework for personalized video search</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2021-gnn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2021-gnn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computed tomography lung parenchymal descriptions in routine radiological reporting have diagnostic and prognostic utility in patients with idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension and pulmonary hypertension associated with lung disease</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/dwivedi-2022-computed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/dwivedi-2022-computed/</guid><description/></item><item><title>PyKale: an ML Library in PyTorch Ecosystem</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</guid><description>&lt;p>PyKale is a library in the PyTorch ecosystem aiming to make machine learning more accessible to interdisciplinary research by bridging gaps between data, software, and end users. Both machine learning experts and end users can do better research with our accessible, scalable, and sustainable design, guided by green machine learning principles. PyKale has a unified pipeline-based API and focuses on multimodal learning and transfer learning for graphs, images, texts, and videos at the moment, with supporting models on deep learning and dimensionality reduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyKale enforces standardization and minimalism, via green machine learning concepts of reducing repetitions and redundancy, reusing existing resources, and recycling learning models across areas. PyKale will enable and accelerate interdisciplinary, knowledge-aware machine learning research for graphs, images, texts, and videos in applications including bioinformatics, graph analysis, image/video recognition, and medical imaging, with an overarching theme of leveraging knowledge from multiple sources for accurate and interpretable prediction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncertainty Est. for Landmark Localisation</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automatic anatomical landmark localisation has made great strides by leveraging deep learning methods in recent years. The ability to quantify the uncertainty of these predictions is a vital ingredient needed to see these methods adopted in clinical use, where it is imperative that erroneous predictions are caught and corrected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Quantile Binning, a data-driven method to categorise predictions by uncertainty with estimated error bounds. This framework can be applied to any continuous uncertainty measure, allowing straightforward identification of the best subset of predictions with accompanying estimated error bounds. We facilitate easy comparison between uncertainty measures by constructing two evaluation metrics derived from Quantile Binning. We demonstrate this framework by comparing and contrasting three uncertainty measures (a baseline, the current gold standard, and a proposed method combining aspects of the two), across two datasets (one easy, one hard) and two heatmap-based landmark localisation model paradigms (U-Net based and patch-based). We conclude by illustrating how filtering out gross mispredictions caught in our Quantile Bins significantly improves the proportion of predictions under an acceptable error threshold, and offer recommendations on which uncertainty measure to use and how to use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low-Bias Evaluation of Drug-Target Interaction</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/dti-graph-eval/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/dti-graph-eval/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is in collaboration with AstraZeneca.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drug-target interaction (DTI) prediction is important in drug discovery and chemogenomics studies. Machine learning, particularly deep learning, has advanced this area significantly over the past few years. However, a significant gap between the performance reported in academic papers and that in practical drug discovery settings, e.g. the random-split-based evaluation strategy tends to be too optimistic in estimating the prediction performance in real-world settings. Such performance gap is largely due to hidden data bias in experimental datasets and inappropriate data split.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we construct a low-bias DTI dataset and study more challenging data split strategies to improve performance evaluation for real-world settings. Specifically, we study the data bias in a popular DTI dataset, BindingDB, and re-evaluate the prediction performance of three state-of-the-art deep learning models using five different data split strategies: random split, cold drug split, scaffold split, and two hierarchical-clustering-based splits. In addition, we comprehensively examine six performance metrics. Our experimental results confirm the overoptimism of the popular random split and show that hierarchical-clustering-based splits are far more challenging and can provide potentially more useful assessment of model generalizability in real-world DTI prediction settings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hierarchical clustering split for low-bias evaluation of drug-target interaction prediction</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bai-2021-hierarchical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bai-2021-hierarchical/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Improving Negative Sampling in Graph Neural Networks for Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/herghelegiu-2021-improving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/herghelegiu-2021-improving/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evaluating transformers for lightweight action recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/koot-2021-evaluating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/koot-2021-evaluating/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Human-In-The-Loop DL for Cardiac CT/MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/cardiac-hitl-dl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/cardiac-hitl-dl/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is an &lt;a href="https://fundingawards.nihr.ac.uk/award/AI_AWARD01706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NIHR AI in Health and Care Award&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular and pulmonary diseases account for close to half of all deaths in the UK. Diagnosing individuals with such conditions correctly and predicting whether they will respond to treatment is important to guide therapeutic intervention and achieve optimal outcomes. Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI) and computed tomography (CT) scans are key to cardiac and pulmonary diagnosis. Current assessments are made by manual measurements (contours or landmarks) to derive meaningful information of heart function, or physiological parameters that are time-consuming and suffer from variability between individuals due to human error. Artificial intelligence using deep learning is pushing the limit of image analysis to an unprecedented level. Recently, a deep learning-based method trained on scans with high variability has been shown to achieve fully automated assessment of the left ventricle (LV) on CMRI. However, this level of automation has not been achieved for the right ventricle (RV) or the atrial chambers. RV failure is the key determinant of death in many cardiac conditions, but accurate RV assessment by human observers is challenging due to the more subtle anatomy and the thinner structures. There is a real clinical need to develop a fully automated assessment of the RV and all four cardiac chambers to derive meaningful physiological parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this project is to develop an interactive human-in-the-loop multi-stage deep learning method to measure the health of the heart in large cohorts of patients with different cardiac and pulmonary conditions, scanned on different MRI/CT machines. This method will automatically generate physiological parameters and assess their ability to automatically predict treatment response and early death. In addition, we will assess the ability of machine learning to directly assess complex shape or/and motion of the heart to make a prognostic assessment from the automatic drawings on the heart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Existing contour and landmark detection algorithms (known from our pilot assessments to be suboptimal) will be applied to scans of a large cohort of patients from different hospitals with diverse cardiac and pulmonary conditions. The measurements will be edited by a team of experienced consultants, these revised contours and landmarks will be fed back into the training to achieve an improved segmentation, and the process will repeat three times to achieve ideal accuracy. Feedback will be sought from doctors, imaging experts and patients.The deep learnt assessment of the heart will provide important measurements for predicting therapy response and survival in individuals with cardiac disease. The automatic physiological parameters and assessment of complex shape or/and motion produced by the deep learning approach could revolutionise disease assessment, and improve treatment delivery and patient care. Key advantages are rapid assessment, minimised human error and more consistent reporting of cardiac physiology and function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mixed-order spectral clustering for complex networks</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/ge-2021-mixed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/ge-2021-mixed/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mixed-order Spectral Clustering for Networks</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/mixed-order-clustering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/mixed-order-clustering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spectral clustering (SC) is a popular approach for gaining insights from complex networks. Conventional SC focuses on second-order structures (e.g. edges) without direct consideration of higher-order structures (e.g. triangles). This has motivated SC extensions that directly consider higher-order structures. However, both approaches are limited to considering a single order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address this issue, we propose a novel Mixed-Order Spectral Clustering (MOSC) framework to model both second-order and third-order structures simultaneously. To model mixed-order structures, we propose two new methods based on Graph Laplacian (GL) and Random Walks (RW). MOSC-GL combines edge and triangle adjacency matrices, with theoretical performance guarantee. MOSC-RW combines first-order and second-order random walks for a probabilistic interpretation. Moreover, we design mixed-order cut criteria to enable existing SC methods to preserve mixed-order structures, and develop new mixed-order evaluation metrics for structure-level evaluation. Experiments on community detection and superpixel segmentation show (1) the superior performance of the MOSC methods over existing SC methods, (2) enhanced performance of conventional SC due to mixed-order cut criteria, and (3) new insights of output clusters offered by the mixed-order evaluation metrics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Channel-temporal attention for first-person video domain adaptation</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/liu-2021-channel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/liu-2021-channel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>APRILE: Exploring the molecular mechanisms of drug side effects with explainable graph neural networks</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2021-aprile/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2021-aprile/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Probabilistic rank-one tensor analysis with concurrent regularizations</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2019-probabilistic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2019-probabilistic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>VideoLightFormer: Lightweight action recognition using transformers</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/koot-2021-videolightformer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/koot-2021-videolightformer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multisite Brain fMRI Classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) has no objective diagnosis method despite having a high prevalence. Machine learning has been widely used to develop classification models for ASD using neuroimaging data. Recently, studies have shifted towards using large multi-site neuroimaging datasets to boost the clinical applicability and statistical power of results. However, the classification performance is hindered by the heterogeneous nature of agglomerative datasets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we propose new methods for multi-site autism classification using the Autism Brain Imaging Data Exchange (ABIDE) dataset. We firstly propose a new second-order measure of functional connectivity (FC) named as Tangent Pearson embedding to extract better features for classification. Then we assess the statistical dependence between acquisition sites and FC features, and apply a domain adaptation approach to minimise the site dependence of FC features to improve classification. Our analysis shows that 1) statistical dependence between site and FC features is statistically significant at the 5% level, and 2) extracting second-order features from neuroimaging data and minimising their site dependence can improve over state-of-the-art classification results on the ABIDE dataset, achieving a classification accuracy of 73%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyKale: Knowledge-aware machine learning from multiple sources in python</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2021-pykale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2021-pykale/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Neuropsychiatric disease classification using functional connectomics - results of the connectomics in neuroimaging transfer learning challenge</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schirmer-2021-neuropsychiatric/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schirmer-2021-neuropsychiatric/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Confidence-quantifying landmark localisation for cardiac MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schobs-2021-confidence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schobs-2021-confidence/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pulmonary hypertension in association with lung disease: quantitative CT and artificial intelligence to the rescue? state-of-the-art review</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/dwivedi-2021-pulmonary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/dwivedi-2021-pulmonary/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A machine learning cardiac magnetic resonance approach to extract disease features and automate pulmonary arterial hypertension diagnosis</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/swift-2021-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/swift-2021-machine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hop-hop relation-aware graph neural networks</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2020-hop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2020-hop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Unifying homophily and heterophily network transformation via motifs</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/ge-2020-unifying/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/ge-2020-unifying/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interpretable ML for Cardiac MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/ml-assess-cmr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/ml-assess-cmr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is a &lt;a href="https://grantnav.threesixtygiving.org/grant/360G-Wellcome-215799_Z_19_Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wellcome Trust Innovator Awards: Digital Technologies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular diseases account for 26% of deaths in the UK. Current clinical imaging assessments rely on manual or semi-automated measurements. Emerging approaches focus on individual parts of the heart. We have developed the first tensor-based machine learning approach that holistically assesses the heart and surrounding structures on cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI) scans. We will develop this approach into a tool that can identify patients who respond to treatment or who will die early. Key advantages are rapid holistic assessment, minimal human error and full transparency with direct visualisation of features for the disease. We will assemble a large cohort of CMRI scans from 5, 000 patients with pulmonary hypertension, a severe condition affecting the heart, and assess the ability to predict treatment response and likelihood of early death. This tool will revolutionise disease assessment, and improve treatment delivery and patient care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A feature-importance-aware and robust aggregator for GCN</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2020-feature/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2020-feature/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GripNet: Graph information propagation on supergraph for heterogeneous graphs</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-gripnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-gripnet/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learnable GCN Aggregator</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/learnable-gcn-aggregator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/learnable-gcn-aggregator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neighborhood aggregation is a key step in Graph Convolutional Networks (GCNs) for graph representation learning. Two commonly used aggregators, sum and mean, are designed with the homophily assumption that connected nodes are likely to share the same label. However, real-world graphs are noisy and adjacent nodes do not necessarily imply similarity.Learnable aggregators are proposed in Graph Attention Network (GAT) and Learnable Graph Convolutional Layer (LGCL). However, GAT considers node importance but not the importance of different features. The convolution aggregator in LGCL considers feature importance but it can not directly operate on graphs due to the irregular connectivity and lack of orderliness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this work, we firstly unify the current learnable aggregators in a framework: Learnable Aggregator for GCN (LA-GCN) by introducing a shared auxiliary model that provides a customized schema in neighborhood aggregation. Under this framework, we propose a new model called LA-GCNMask consisting of a new aggregator function,mask aggregator. The auxiliary model learns a specific mask for each neighbor of a given node, allowing both node-level and feature-level attention. This mechanism learns to assign different importance to both nodes and features for prediction, which provides interpretable explanations for prediction and increases the model robustness. Experiments on seven graphs for node classification and graph classification tasks show that LA-GCNMask outperforms the state-of-the-art methods. Moreover, our aggregator can identify both the important nodes and node features simultaneously, which provides a quantified understanding of the relationship between input nodes and the prediction. We further conduct experiments on noisy graphs to evaluate the robustness of our model. Experiments show that LA-GCNMask consistently outperforms the state-of-the-art methods, with up to 15% improvements in terms of accuracy compared to the second best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Geodesically smoothed tensor features for pulmonary hypertension prognosis using the heart and surrounding tissues</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/uthoff-2020-geodesically/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/uthoff-2020-geodesically/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Improving multi-site autism classification based on site-dependence minimisation and second-order functional connectivity</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/kunda-2020-improving/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/kunda-2020-improving/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Side information dependence as a regularizer for analyzing human brain conditions across cognitive experiments</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2020-side/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2020-side/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tri-graph information propagation for polypharmacy side effect prediction</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-tri/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-tri/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Improving whole-brain neural decoding of fMRI with domain adaptation</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2019-improving/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2019-improving/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sturm: Sparse tubal-regularized multilinear regression for fMRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/li-2019-sturm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/li-2019-sturm/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Joint interaction with context operation for collaborative filtering</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bai-2019-joint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bai-2019-joint/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Feature extraction for incomplete data via low-rank tensor decomposition with feature regularization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2018-feature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2018-feature/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Graph node-feature convolution for representation learning</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2018-graph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhang-2018-graph/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rank-one matrix completion with automatic rank estimation via L1-norm regularization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2017-rank/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2017-rank/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tensor rank estimation and completion via CP-based nuclear norm</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2017-tensor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2017-tensor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Motor imagery classification based on bilinear sub-manifold learning of symmetric positive-definite matrices</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xie-2016-motor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xie-2016-motor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bilinear probabilistic canonical correlation analysis via hybrid concatenations</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2017-bilinear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2017-bilinear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multilinear regression for embedded feature selection with application to fMRI analysis</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2017-multilinear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2017-multilinear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>EcoICA: Skewness-based ICA via eigenvectors of cumulant operator</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2016-ecoica/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2016-ecoica/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Proper inner product with mean displacement for gaussian noise invariant ICA</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2016-proper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2016-proper/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning compact binary codes from higher-order tensors via free-form reshaping and binarized multilinear PCA</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2016-learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2016-learning/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Probabilistic rank-one matrix analysis with concurrent regularization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2016-probabilistic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/zhou-2016-probabilistic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning tensor-based features for whole-brain fMRI classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2015-learning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/song-2015-learning/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Semi-orthogonal multilinear PCA with relaxed start</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2015-semi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/shi-2015-semi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning modewise independent components from tensor data using multilinear mixing model</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-learningica/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-learningica/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning canonical correlations of paired tensor sets via tensor-to-vector projection</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-learningcca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-learningcca/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantifying limb movements in epileptic seizures through color-based video analysis</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2012-quantifying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2012-quantifying/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multilinear Subspace Learning: Dimensionality Reduction Of Multidimensional Data</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-multilinear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2013-multilinear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Non-intrusive head movement analysis of videotaped seizures of epileptic origin</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/mandal-2012-non/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/mandal-2012-non/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Markerless video analysis for movement quantification in pediatric epilepsy monitoring</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2011-markerless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2011-markerless/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A survey of multilinear subspace learning for tensor data</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2011-survey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2011-survey/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Regularized common spatial pattern with aggregation for EEG classification in small-sample setting</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2010-regularized/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2010-regularized/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Visualization and clustering of crowd video content in MPCA subspace</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2010-visualization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2010-visualization/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fuzzy key binding strategies based on quantization index modulation (QIM) for biometric encryption (BE) applications</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bui-2009-fuzzy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/bui-2009-fuzzy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A biometric encryption system for the self-exclusion scenario of face recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/martin-2009-biometric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/martin-2009-biometric/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uncorrelated multilinear principal component analysis for unsupervised multilinear subspace learning</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-uncorrelatedpca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-uncorrelatedpca/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Boosting discriminant learners for gait recognition using MPCA features</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-boosting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-boosting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Regularized common spatial patterns with generic learning for EEG signal classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-regularized/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-regularized/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Face recognition with biometric encryption for privacy-enhancing self-exclusion</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-face/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-face/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gaussian kernel optimization for pattern classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/wang-2009-gaussian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/wang-2009-gaussian/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A review on face and gait recognition: system, data and algorithms</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-review/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A taxonomy of emerging multilinear discriminant analysis solutions for biometric signal recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-taxonomy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-taxonomy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uncorrelated multilinear discriminant analysis with regularization and aggregation for tensor object recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-uncorrelatedlda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2009-uncorrelatedlda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multilinear Subspace Learning for Face and Gait Recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/haiping-ph-dthesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/haiping-ph-dthesis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uncorrelated multilinear principal component analysis through successive variance maximization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-uncorrelatedpca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-uncorrelatedpca/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A full-body layered deformable model for automatic model-based gait recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-full/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-full/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Method, software, and device for hiding data in binary image, while preserving image quality</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/kot-2008-method/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/kot-2008-method/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MPCA: Multilinear principal component analysis of tensor objects</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-mpca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2008-mpca/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Boosting LDA with regularization on MPCA features for gait recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2007-boosting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2007-boosting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uncorrelated multilinear discriminant analysis with regularization for gait recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2007-uncorrelated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2007-uncorrelated/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gait recognition through MPCA plus LDA</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-gait/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-gait/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multilinear principal component analysis of tensor objects for recognition</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-multilinear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-multilinear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Coarse-to-fine pedestrian localization and silhouette extraction for the gait challenge data sets</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-coarse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-coarse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A layered deformable model for gait analysis</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-layered/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2006-layered/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Binary image watermarking through blurring and biased binarization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2005-binary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2005-binary/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Distance-reciprocal distortion measure for binary document images</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2004-distance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2004-distance/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Binary image watermarking through biased binarization</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2003-binary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2003-binary/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Secure data hiding in binary document images for authentication</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2003-secure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2003-secure/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effective and efficient fingerprint image postprocessing</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-effective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-effective/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Watermark embedding in DC components of DCT for binary images</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-watermark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-watermark/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An objective distortion measure for binary document images based on human visual perception</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-objective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2002-objective/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>