<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hao Xu | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/hao-xu/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/hao-xu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Hao Xu</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/hao-xu/avatar_hu588829865c45fdc1de4e91587258ccd0_40823_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Hao Xu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/hao-xu/</link></image><item><title>PyKale: open-source multimodal learning software library</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</guid><description>&lt;p>PyKale is a library in the PyTorch ecosystem aiming to make machine learning more accessible to interdisciplinary research by bridging gaps between data, software, and end users. Both machine learning experts and end users can do better research with our accessible, scalable, and sustainable design, guided by green machine learning principles. PyKale has a unified pipeline-based API and focuses on multimodal learning and transfer learning for graphs, images, texts, and videos at the moment, with supporting models on deep learning and dimensionality reduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyKale enforces standardization and minimalism, via green machine learning concepts of reducing repetitions and redundancy, reusing existing resources, and recycling learning models across areas. PyKale will enable and accelerate interdisciplinary, knowledge-aware machine learning research for graphs, images, texts, and videos in applications including bioinformatics, graph analysis, image/video recognition, and medical imaging, with an overarching theme of leveraging knowledge from multiple sources for accurate and interpretable prediction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>APRILE: Exploring the molecular mechanisms of drug side effects with explainable graph neural networks</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2021-aprile/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2021-aprile/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GripNet: Graph information propagation on supergraph for heterogeneous graphs</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-gripnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-gripnet/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tri-graph information propagation for polypharmacy side effect prediction</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-tri/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/xu-2020-tri/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>