<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selected | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/selected/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/selected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Selected</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/media/icon_huc5fd9f1b4f03f2d64add7afcb374c1e6_29577_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Selected</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/tag/selected/</link></image><item><title>Inverse protein folding via denoising diffusion</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/inverse-protein-folding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/inverse-protein-folding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Inverse protein folding generates valid amino acid sequences that can fold into a desired protein structure, with recent deep-learning advances showing significant potential and competitive performance. However, challenges remain in predicting highly uncertain regions, such as those with loops and disorders. To tackle such low-confidence residue prediction, we propose a &lt;strong>Ma&lt;/strong>sk &lt;strong>p&lt;/strong>rior-guided denoising &lt;strong>Diff&lt;/strong>usion (&lt;strong>MapDiff&lt;/strong>) framework that accurately captures both structural and residue interactions for inverse protein folding. MapDiff is a discrete diffusion probabilistic model that iteratively generates amino acid sequences with reduced noise, conditioned on a given protein backbone. To incorporate structural and residue interactions, we develop a graph-based denoising network with a mask prior pre-training strategy. Moreover, in the generative process, we combine the denoising diffusion implicit model with Monte-Carlo dropout to improve uncertainty estimation. Evaluation on four challenging sequence design benchmarks shows that MapDiff significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods. Furthermore, the in-silico sequences generated by MapDiff closely resemble the physico-chemical and structural characteristics of native proteins across different protein families and architectures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multimodal VAE for low-cost cardiac assessment</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/multimodal-vae-low-cost-cardiac/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/multimodal-vae-low-cost-cardiac/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is a &lt;a href="https://grantnav.threesixtygiving.org/grant/360G-Wellcome-215799_Z_19_Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wellcome Trust Innovator Awards: Digital Technologies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular diseases account for 26% of deaths in the UK. Current clinical imaging assessments rely on manual or semi-automated measurements. Emerging approaches focus on individual parts of the heart. We have developed the first tensor-based machine learning approach that holistically assesses the heart and surrounding structures on cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI) scans. We will develop this approach into a tool that can identify patients who respond to treatment or who will die early. Key advantages are rapid holistic assessment, minimal human error and full transparency with direct visualisation of features for the disease. We will assemble a large cohort of CMRI scans from 5, 000 patients with pulmonary hypertension, a severe condition affecting the heart, and assess the ability to predict treatment response and likelihood of early death. This tool will revolutionise disease assessment, and improve treatment delivery and patient care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Molecular property prediction via line graph transformer</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/molecular-property-prediction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/molecular-property-prediction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Molecular property prediction with deep learning has gained much attention over the past years. Owing to the scarcity of labeled molecules, there has been growing interest in self-supervised learning methods that learn generalizable molecular representations from unlabeled data. Molecules are typically treated as 2D topological graphs in modeling, but it has been discovered that their 3D geometry is of great importance in determining molecular functionalities. In this paper, we propose the Geometry-aware line graph transformer (Galformer) pre-training, a novel self-supervised learning framework that aims to enhance molecular representation learning with 2D and 3D modalities. Specifically, we first design a dual-modality line graph transformer backbone to encode the topological and geometric information of a molecule. The designed backbone incorporates effective structural encodings to capture graph structures from both modalities. Then we devise two complementary pre-training tasks at the inter and intra-modality levels. These tasks provide properly supervised information and extract discriminative 2D and 3D knowledge from unlabeled molecules. Finally, we evaluate Galformer against six state-of-the-art baselines on twelve property prediction benchmarks via downstream fine-tuning. Experimental results show that Galformer consistently outperforms all baselines on both classification and regression tasks, demonstrating its effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drug–target interaction prediction via bilinear attention network</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/drug-target-interaction-prediction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/drug-target-interaction-prediction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Predicting drug–target interaction is key for drug discovery. Recent deep learning-based methods show promising performance, but two challenges remain: how to explicitly model and learn local interactions between drugs and targets for better prediction and interpretation and how to optimize generalization performance of predictions on novel drug–target pairs. Here, we present &lt;strong>DrugBAN&lt;/strong>, a deep &lt;strong>B&lt;/strong>ilinear &lt;strong>A&lt;/strong>ttention &lt;strong>N&lt;/strong>etwork (&lt;strong>BAN&lt;/strong>) framework with domain adaptation to explicitly learn pairwise local interactions between drugs and targets, and adapt in response to out-of-distribution data. DrugBAN works on drug molecular graphs and target protein sequences to perform prediction, with conditional domain adversarial learning to align learned interaction representations across different distributions for better generalization on novel drug–target pairs. Experiments on three benchmark datasets under both in-domain and cross-domain settings show that DrugBAN achieves the best overall performance against five state-of-the-art baseline models. Moreover, visualizing the learned bilinear attention map provides interpretable insights from prediction results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyKale: open-source multimodal learning software library</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</guid><description>&lt;p>PyKale is a library in the PyTorch ecosystem aiming to make machine learning more accessible to interdisciplinary research by bridging gaps between data, software, and end users. Both machine learning experts and end users can do better research with our accessible, scalable, and sustainable design, guided by green machine learning principles. PyKale has a unified pipeline-based API and focuses on multimodal learning and transfer learning for graphs, images, texts, and videos at the moment, with supporting models on deep learning and dimensionality reduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyKale enforces standardization and minimalism, via green machine learning concepts of reducing repetitions and redundancy, reusing existing resources, and recycling learning models across areas. PyKale will enable and accelerate interdisciplinary, knowledge-aware machine learning research for graphs, images, texts, and videos in applications including bioinformatics, graph analysis, image/video recognition, and medical imaging, with an overarching theme of leveraging knowledge from multiple sources for accurate and interpretable prediction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multisite brain fMRI classification</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/brain-fmri-multisite/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) has no objective diagnosis method despite having a high prevalence. Machine learning has been widely used to develop classification models for ASD using neuroimaging data. Recently, studies have shifted towards using large multi-site neuroimaging datasets to boost the clinical applicability and statistical power of results. However, the classification performance is hindered by the heterogeneous nature of agglomerative datasets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we propose new methods for multi-site autism classification using the Autism Brain Imaging Data Exchange (ABIDE) dataset. We firstly propose a new second-order measure of functional connectivity (FC) named as Tangent Pearson embedding to extract better features for classification. Then we assess the statistical dependence between acquisition sites and FC features, and apply a domain adaptation approach to minimise the site dependence of FC features to improve classification. Our analysis shows that 1) statistical dependence between site and FC features is statistically significant at the 5% level, and 2) extracting second-order features from neuroimaging data and minimising their site dependence can improve over state-of-the-art classification results on the ABIDE dataset, achieving a classification accuracy of 73%.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>