<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lawrence Schobs | Haiping Lu</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/lawrence-schobs/</link><atom:link href="https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/lawrence-schobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Lawrence Schobs</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 by Haiping Lu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/lawrence-schobs/avatar_hu37ff5d6e72c884b70e30bc9057815fb2_37552_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Lawrence Schobs</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/authors/lawrence-schobs/</link></image><item><title>PyKale: an ML Library in PyTorch Ecosystem</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/pykale/</guid><description>&lt;p>PyKale is a library in the PyTorch ecosystem aiming to make machine learning more accessible to interdisciplinary research by bridging gaps between data, software, and end users. Both machine learning experts and end users can do better research with our accessible, scalable, and sustainable design, guided by green machine learning principles. PyKale has a unified pipeline-based API and focuses on multimodal learning and transfer learning for graphs, images, texts, and videos at the moment, with supporting models on deep learning and dimensionality reduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyKale enforces standardization and minimalism, via green machine learning concepts of reducing repetitions and redundancy, reusing existing resources, and recycling learning models across areas. PyKale will enable and accelerate interdisciplinary, knowledge-aware machine learning research for graphs, images, texts, and videos in applications including bioinformatics, graph analysis, image/video recognition, and medical imaging, with an overarching theme of leveraging knowledge from multiple sources for accurate and interpretable prediction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncertainty Est. for Landmark Localisation</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/project/landmark-uncertainty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automatic anatomical landmark localisation has made great strides by leveraging deep learning methods in recent years. The ability to quantify the uncertainty of these predictions is a vital ingredient needed to see these methods adopted in clinical use, where it is imperative that erroneous predictions are caught and corrected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Quantile Binning, a data-driven method to categorise predictions by uncertainty with estimated error bounds. This framework can be applied to any continuous uncertainty measure, allowing straightforward identification of the best subset of predictions with accompanying estimated error bounds. We facilitate easy comparison between uncertainty measures by constructing two evaluation metrics derived from Quantile Binning. We demonstrate this framework by comparing and contrasting three uncertainty measures (a baseline, the current gold standard, and a proposed method combining aspects of the two), across two datasets (one easy, one hard) and two heatmap-based landmark localisation model paradigms (U-Net based and patch-based). We conclude by illustrating how filtering out gross mispredictions caught in our Quantile Bins significantly improves the proportion of predictions under an acceptable error threshold, and offer recommendations on which uncertainty measure to use and how to use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyKale: Knowledge-aware machine learning from multiple sources in python</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2021-pykale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/lu-2021-pykale/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Confidence-quantifying landmark localisation for cardiac MRI</title><link>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schobs-2021-confidence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haipinglu.github.io/publication/schobs-2021-confidence/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>